<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="weston_hdr_static_metadata">

  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2019 Intel
    Copyright _ 2022 NVIDIA Corporation


    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="hdr_surface" version="1">

    <description summary="hdr surface">
      An extension interface to the wl_surface object to set the HDR static metadata
      associated with the surface.
    </description>

    <request name="set_metadata">
      <description summary="set the HDR static metadata for a surface">
        Set the HDR static metadata for the associated wl_surface. The HDR static
        metadata state is double buffered and will be applied on the next
        wl_surface::commit.
      </description>
      <arg name="display_primary_r_x" type="fixed" summary="Red primary X"/>
      <arg name="display_primary_r_y" type="fixed" summary="Red primary Y"/>
      <arg name="display_primary_g_x" type="fixed" summary="Green primary X"/>
      <arg name="display_primary_g_y" type="fixed" summary="Green primary Y"/>
      <arg name="display_primary_b_x" type="fixed" summary="Blue primary X"/>
      <arg name="display_primary_b_y" type="fixed" summary="Blue primary Y"/>
      <arg name="white_point_x" type="fixed" summary="White point X"/>
      <arg name="white_point_y" type="fixed" summary="White point Y"/>
      <arg name="min_luminance" type="fixed" summary="Minimum luminance"/>
      <arg name="max_luminance" type="fixed" summary="Maximum luminance"/>
      <arg name="max_cll" type="uint" summary="Maximum content light level"/>
      <arg name="max_fall" type="uint" summary="Maximum frame-average light level"/>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface" summary="the surface"/>
    </request>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the hdr_surface object">
        Destroying this object, destroys the HDR metadata associated with the
        surface and the surface will be considered as an SDR surface from the
        next wl_surface::commit.
      </description>
      <arg name="surface" type="object" interface="wl_surface" summary="the surface"/>
    </request>
  </interface>

</protocol>
